Guo Zijian's move to break into small units
is exactly what urban warfare calls for.
He caught on just in time.
But given their urban warfare skills,
they're just buying a little more time.
It has no real tactical significance.
Brigade Commander, we have new intel.
Which unit is at this position?
Why has there been no movement?
It's confirmed.
It's the unit from the highway,
the crippled Red Army 1st Company.
What are they doing hiding there?
Probably spooked from the beating they took.
Their personnel and equipment are well hidden.
And due to their solid troop deployment,
our assault teams can't get close.
In that case,
keep a close eye on them.
Yes, sir.
All companies, don't panic.
Establish a defensive line immediately.
What's going on?
We're under heavy electromagnetic interference.
Start frequency hopping. Re-establish comms.
Yes, sir.
1st Company, 2nd Company, do you copy?
The Red force's two reinforced companies
are basically wiped out.
Another half-dead one doesn't dare come out.
Also, the air assault forces given to them,
they haven't even used yet.
Their so-called "new-type" capabilities
are nowhere to be seen.
This battle is just...
Boring.
It really is unsatisfying.
I really don't know what Deputy Commander Liang
means by pulling this stunt.
Guo Zijian's Wind Rider Battalion
hasn't integrated well at all.
The so-called Cube is just a single module.
To be used as our test subjects,
they're completely unqualified.
I really don't know if Old Liang
let that news report
from a while back
go to his head.
Commander, you read that article in the military paper,
"The Concerns of a New-type Battalion Commander," right?
That kid Guo Zijian
got pretty popular because of that report.
I read it.
The article was quite practical.
The issues raised were deep,
and his thoughts on future battlefields were spot on.
But looking at it now,
they are merely
just thoughts.
This is the so-called,
"The greater the ability,
the greater the pressure."
Exactly.
Just look at our Blue Force community,
the most famous being Di Yunfeng.
He was crowned as the Blue Force Commander.
If he fights well, it's expected.
If he fights poorly,
he's not just embarrassing himself.
Commander, hearing you say this,
could it be sour grapes?
What are you saying?
However,
if we can make Guo Zijian's Wind Rider Battalion
expose its problems more thoroughly,
consider it a grand gift
from an old rival like me.
Right.
It's guarded by a special ops unit.
If I'm not mistaken,
that's the Blue Force command post.
Do we strike?
Of course we do.
But with just the few of us,
I'm afraid we're no match for them.
Then what's the plan?
Do you have the special ops frequency?
I do.
Good.
Contact Yang Maolin immediately.
No good. The jamming is too strong now.
My headset matches the Special Ops team's.
Let me try the intercom.
But even the radios are down.
The intercom frequency is so low,
it'll be even worse, right?
The jamming system mainly targets
the 2G to 4G frequency bands.
The transmission frequencies of these bands
are all above 2,000 hertz.
But the intercom is below 500 hertz,
so it avoids the jamming.
But walkie-talkies have a limited range.
We are equipped with
the latest short-wave intercom system.
We should be able to connect.
Honey Badger, Honey Badger.
Cheetah calling Honey Badger.
This is Honey Badger. Go ahead, Cheetah.
I found a suspected command center.
I need you to clear it personally.
Send me the coordinates.
I'll head there right away.
Remember the location.
It's an underground tunnel.
I'll send you the exact coordinates now.
We'll evacuate first.
Move out.
Cheetah, Cheetah.
Just now, the assault groups of Companies 2 and 3
took heavy fire from scattered infantry rockets.
The troops are scattered.
Please handle at your discretion.
Copy that.
Deputy Company Commander Xu,
return immediately to the company's equipment hideout,
and lead the team toward the town hall.
Listen up.
Once you move out,
you must keep the soldiers dispersed
and provide cross-cover for the heavy equipment.
Understood.
Those bastards have rockets,
but they're afraid of infantry.
What about you?
I'll head to the flanks of the town hall
to recover the scattered equipment of Companies 2 and 3.
Remember,
move fast.
Yes, sir.
Dongfang Qingtian,
why didn't you promptly report the attack on Companies 2 and 3?
The situation was critical just now.
I was just about to report it.
Where is your attack drone?
You trained with it for so long,
is it just for show?
Why didn't you provide support?
Staff Officer Zeng,
we are currently equipped with only one attack drone,
and it carries very few missiles.
I wanted to find the core target before striking.
Alright, I understand.
From now on,
you follow my command.
Coordinate with me to complete the strike on the town hall.
I will provide you with precise strike coordinates.
Copy that.
We missed that team just now.
Thought a few more teams would show up.
Didn't expect
only three little kittens to show up.
What a letdown.
Judging by this style,
it must be Old Yang.
So smart.
You got it right.
This is all good gear.
Take it.
Thanks, Deputy Company Commander.
Don't thank me.
Losing to you
is no disgrace.
Wild Wolf, Wild Wolf.
Report your status.
This is Wild Wolf.
Four Red-beaked Birds have been caged.
Copy that.
Not bad, Old Yang.
You nailed my accent.
When did you practice that?
Just a little casual practice.
Coordinates sent.
Target coordinates sent.
Fire!
Yes, sir!
Staff Officer Zeng.
The Blue Force is probably done for.
That was probably just a spent force.
Okay.
Deputy Company Commander Xu,
take a dozen men yourself
and cut in from the right rear of the town government building.
From there, you can access the roof directly.
Once we take the high ground,
the rest of the battle will be easy.
Yes, sir.
Until the very end,
don't declare victory too soon.
Smart kid.
He even used attack drones.
He turned the tables beautifully.
Zeng Muhan performed excellently this time.
Proving the battalion commander was right to trust him.
Adversity reveals true strength.
And turbulent times reveal heroes.
Those brats in the First Company.
When Zeng Muhan became their company commander,
they were completely against it.
But look at them now.
Wasn't it Zeng Muhan
who dragged them out of the mud?
Fall back!
We won!
Great work!
Congratulations!
Good work, good work.
Good.
Reporting!
Battalion Commander!
Objective secured!
The exercise is over.
No.
That's not right.
The Blue Force's command post never appeared.
How could it be over?
What are you so happy about?
Do you want the hostage?
Freshly captured hostage.
Great value.
Guaranteed authentic.
The King of Soldiers was captured.
It really is the King of Soldiers.
He'd be better off dead.
I heard the King of Soldiers
used to be in their brigade.
They're close.
Did he defect?
The battle is over.
Let the troops disperse.
We, the Blue Force,
suggest a truce.
If you refuse to accept this,
first,
there are still hostages in the tunnel.
We'll kill them one by one.
Second,
if you still want to fight,
that's fine too.
But it's essentially a bayonet fight.
There's no point anymore.
Commander Ma,
notify Exercise Control.
The exercise is over.
The result is pending.
Yes, sir.
Attention, Exercise Control.
The exercise ends here.
The result is pending.
Connect me via video.
I need to speak to
the commanders in the observation group.
Yes, sir.
Commanders,
Professor Zhang.
The performance of the Wind Rider Battalion just now,
as you all saw,
had too many problems
for me to review one by one.
Today's observation concludes here.
Later, I will submit a detailed report
to all the commanders.
Old Long,
do you think we
had a bit too much fun?
With so many people watching,
Deputy Corps Commander Liang might lose face.
The value of the Blue Force's existence
is to expose
the problems within the Red Force.
Losing face now
is better than losing it later.
Guo Zijian's Wind Rider Battalion
has too many problems.
The more fun we have,
the more it helps them.
Didn't I tell you?
Just consider this time
a great gift from us to them.
Our Value Cube
really lost a lot of face today.
Even though
today's battle
ended up like this,
I personally feel
there are still many areas
that are commendable.
If there are problems,
we solve them.
There's no need to give up on ourselves.
I think what we really need to reflect on is
if we ever encounter
the same situation again in the future,
we absolutely must not
let our emotions
dictate our actions anymore.
Unless,
this time,
our Wind Rider Battalion
was truly crushed by them.
Win or lose,
I, Guo Zijian, can accept it.
But look at us.
From start to finish today,
our Cube didn't even spin.
It was all just individual modules spinning on their own.
I want to apologize first.
The first mistake today
was my fault.
I really wasn't in a good mood today,
and I couldn't concentrate for a while.
You two...
Didn't you feel it today,
that the atmosphere in this command vehicle
was off from start to finish?
You,
the chief staff officer.
And you,
the battalion commander.
You two are the core figures of this exercise.
With emotional issues between the two of you,
how can the Cube spin?
Even if this Cube did spin,
it would be spinning recklessly,
spinning blindly and in chaos.
Sang Haitian!
Here!
The battle is over.
You have a very important mission to complete.
Awaiting your orders, sir!
I guarantee mission success!
Bring my Wind Rider Battalion
back to me completely intact.
If it's missing a single screw,
I'll hold you responsible.
Rest assured, Commissar.
I guarantee mission success!
As for the emotional issues,
now is not the time to resolve them.
Once we return to the camp,
get well fed and rested,
and calm down,
we can talk then.
Understood?
I guarantee we won't discuss emotions.
Guo Zijian!
Here!
The Brigade Commander has something to say to you.
Guo Zijian!
Here!
Do you have anything you want to say to me?
Reporting to the Brigade Commander,
I have nothing to say.
Let me tell you, Guo Zijian.
This battle,
on the surface, ended in a draw.
But it also exposed many problems.
Exposing them now
might hurt our pride,
but for the long-term development of your Value Cube,
it's not a bad thing.
If you
can't even see this point,
your role as Wind Rider Battalion Commander
is completely in vain.
I hope
you can be a qualified commander.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, Brigade Commander.
I won't let you down.
Battalion Commander Guo...
That's enough.
We'll listen to our leaders.
The issues we need to discuss
will not be discussed here.
When we leave in a little while,
Yang Maolin and Liang Hong,
you'll come with me.
That won't be necessary.
Instructor.
I'll go with you.
Alright.
Feeling useless?
What do you mean, nodding and shaking your head?
Battalion Commander,
please don't make me talk.
You know Long Yuanshan best in our battalion.
You must tell me the truth.
Actually,
from the beginning when Staff Officer Zeng spotted them,
Brigade Commander Long had already set a trap.
He didn't capture Staff Officer Zeng right away
because he thought
the few men Zeng led were of little value.
I see.
Good thing he didn't capture Zeng Muhan.
Otherwise, we would've lost even worse.
Brigade Commander Long knows me too well.
I can't beat him.
What if I join you?
Could the two of us beat him?
Then it should be fifty-fifty.
Is Brigade Commander Long really that tough?
Battalion Commander,
didn't you just experience it yourself?
Yang Maolin,
let me tell you,
no one is invincible.
One day,
we will definitely defeat Long Yuanshan.
I've already made the calls.
Your mother's surgery was very successful.
She's out of danger now.
Don't worry.
Once we get back,
you can go see your mother first.
I'll handle your leave.
Thank you, Instructor.
Liang Hong,
with such a big family emergency,
why did you wait until the end of the exercise
to tell me?
Our unit
isn't completely heartless.
Of course,
your willingness to put the greater good
before your own family
is a spirit
we should all learn from.
But
some things are just too hard to shoulder
all by yourself.
Have you noticed
that our Wind Rider Battalion
is full of heroes,
but why is it
that every time we're grouped together,
the results are less than ideal?
Don't you think
this is also one of the reasons
our Value Cube has never
truly started working?
You guys love taking on every hardship
all by yourselves,
and refuse to ask for help.
Thank you, Instructor.
This family emergency
happened a bit too suddenly,
right during the exercise.
I know where my duty lies.
On this point,
I trust you completely.
The reason Guo Zijian lost his temper with you
was because we didn't do well in this exercise.
He was anxious, so he lashed out.
I'll definitely give him a good scolding.
He didn't do anything wrong.
I was the one who wasn't professional enough.
You two can be quite cute sometimes.
He just asked you to go back with him.
You didn't want to share a car with him.
And now you're speaking up for him again.
I just don't want to see him right now.
Maybe I'm really not fit
to be his
chief of staff.
Liang Hong.
We've been
colleagues,
working together
for quite some time now.
My experience tells me
if you, Liang Hong,
can't be this chief of staff,
then no one else can.
And I firmly believe
the Sword and Rainbow
duo will one day
become truly invincible.
Instructor, why are you also...
Liang Hong.
I really,
truly love
the Sword and Rainbow duo.
I strongly believe
that as long as you two
are in the Wind Rider Battalion,
our Value Cube
will soon
truly start turning.
But the prerequisite
is that we must deal with
Guo Zijian's awful temper.
Thanks.
After talking to you,
I feel a lot better.
Your sister-in-law
got me some green tea.
It's pretty good.
Try some.
It's tinder-dry.
Have a sip
to cool down.
How can you still drink tea at a time like this?
A time like what?
Regarding this exercise,
I conducted a Debriefing.
The more I think about it, the angrier I get.
How could we fight such a terrible battle?
This time,
our Wind Rider Battalion
completely humiliated ourselves.
Do you feel like
there's no way
to answer to the brigade commander who trusted you?
And even less of a way
to answer to all the troops of the Wind Rider Battalion?
More importantly,
there's no way
to answer to yourself?
Yeah.
I can't answer to anyone.
It's true.
Liang Hong said the same thing.
Where is she?
She hasn't shown her face since getting back.
Tell her to come over for a meeting.
For a Debriefing.
What Debriefing?
Liang Hong
has already submitted her transfer request.
Transfer?
Transfer where?
I don't know.
But her transfer report has already been submitted.
Submitted to whom?
I'm her superior!
To the brigade commander.
This is absurd!
Why didn't you stop her?
I'm going to find her.
Hong Xiafei
Battalion Commander Guo
Where's Liang Hong?
She left.
She left?
The report hasn't been approved yet.
Who said she could leave?
Before the exercise started,
her mother was hospitalized with a heart condition.
She originally wanted to take a leave to go back,
but the exercise delayed her.
Now that the exercise is over,
shouldn't she be allowed to go see her?
Hospitalized?
Why didn't she tell me beforehand?
Did you even give her a chance to explain?
You're unreasonable and only know how to yell.
When is she coming back?
That depends on when Battalion Commander Guo approves
the transfer report.
What report?
If she contacts you,
you tell her
to drop the idea of a transfer.
I'll never let her leave the Wind Rider Battalion.
Let him fret.
The truth will come out.
I disappointed everyone today.
I directly lead the Wind Rider Battalion's development.
If anything happens,
I will face it calmly.
So please speak your minds freely.
Deputy Corps Commander Liang and I are old friends,
but personal feelings aside,
we must stick to the facts.
Regarding the Wind Rider Battalion,
my current opinion
is exactly the same as it was initially.
I can sum it up simply:
Neither fish nor fowl, and completely unnecessary.
I remember when the 8th Group Army
when training the new-type forces' core members,
I went there to lecture and conduct research.
At that time,
regarding the formation of such a unit,
I raised my objections.
It's very simple.
There is no need.
First,
the army's Combined Arms Battalions are already at scale.
Plus, with their diverse branches and types,
the development of the Combined Arms Battalion
is itself divided into several levels.
There is no need to form new force units.
Second,
the framework of the Wind Rider Battalion
is built on the Combined Arms Battalion's framework,
with a few
Special Ops Battalion functions added,
plus a few new-type technologies.
Isn't this just a mishmash?
This can't be called innovation at all.
Third,
the Wind Rider Battalion's force deployment and combination
is simply nonsense.
Setting everything else aside,
take its long-range artillery and air assault forces,
they were never used like this in the past,
they aren't now,
and in the future,
they certainly won't be either.
These opinions of mine
are not fabricated out of thin air,
nor are they groundless.
They are based on my own practical research,
as well as discussions with other experts.
Deputy Corps Commander Liang might
feel a bit uncomfortable hearing this,
but I can't hold anything back.
Not at all.
I'm not wearing a bulletproof vest today,
nor am I wearing earplugs.
I said
everyone should speak freely.
In that case,
Professor Xu,
why don't you share your thoughts?
Professor Zhang
is the fiercest opposition.
I'm actually a bit worried about him.
A sharp blade like him,
won't he end up hurting Deputy Commander Liang?
If Liang Beihua
gets hurt that easily,
then his rank as a general
is seriously inflated.
Recently,
the media's coverage of Wind Rider Battalion and Hurricane,
the two pioneer battalions,
focused heavily on their training.
Looking at it now,
the timing was a bit premature.
Of course,
as for how we should view Wind Rider Battalion,
and how we view Guo Zijian,
the media only shows the surface.
It's still too early to tell.
If right now,
he can't even get past Long Yuanshan,
how can he face a future war?
So,
how will this discussion end?
How will it end?
The feedback...
Bundle it up,
and let Liang Beihua take it back to slowly digest.
Don't worry about him getting indigestion.
Since he wants to boldly innovate,
then whichever burden is the heaviest,
that's the one he has to carry.
After all,
as for what Wind Rider Battalion will eventually become,
Guo Zijian
is certainly important,
but Liang Beihua
is the true architect.
Done fighting?
Old Sang.
I think in the past,
I was too focused on the integration of hardware.
As for the integration between people,
I thought too little about it.
The turning of the cube
can't rely solely on
the modules and the main axis.
It also requires a centripetal force.
I haven't done well in this area.
I will correct it from now on.
Also,
as for your suggestions,
I'll definitely be more open to them from now on.
Without you, the Wind Rider Battalion
really wouldn't be able to turn.
I have my own problems, too.
I tend to repeat myself when I speak.
I'll make sure to correct that, too.
Commander Guo!
Staff Officer Liang is back!
Where?
Almost here!
Hong Xiafei.
Come here.
Come here!
Let's box.
Such a perfect opportunity.
Boxing, huh?
What are you laughing at? Be serious.
Boxing is mainly about...
Is your mother doing alright?
Should I have the unit put in a word with the hospital
to look after her?
No need.
When is she being discharged?
Do you have something to say to me?
I'm sorry.
I've been reflecting on myself these past few days.
Why
didn't you tell me
about your mother's illness?
Because this has nothing to do with you.
No, of course it does.
You said
we are the kind of comrades who, in battle,
can watch each other's backs.
Ever since the Wind Rider Battalion was founded,
no matter what happened,
you've always stood behind me and supported me.
Yet, when you needed me,
I failed to be a companion
you could trust.
I didn't do well in this regard.
I apologize to you.
The reason I didn't tell you
is because it's a private matter.
I didn't want my private affairs to affect the exercise.
But I still overestimated myself.
I still let my private affairs distract me.
So,
as a professional soldier,
this is where I fell short.
Although I often forget this myself,
I still have to tell you,
you're only human.
Not a machine.
Don't think you're omnipotent.
Thanks for telling me I'm human.
You're the machine.
Since we both have
areas where we fell short,
then we're even.
I believe
that since we're partners,
we need to be honest with each other from now on.
We can't let misunderstandings
affect our work.
What did you say?
"From now on"?
Yes.
Stay.
I need someone as excellent as you
to help me turn the Value Cube.
And what if I say no?
Then I'll try another way.
If that doesn't work,
I'll try yet another.
Either way, I won't let you leave the Wind Rider Battalion.
Battalion Commander Guo, are you being unreasonable now?
In short,
you won't regret
the decision to stay today.
Since you put it that way,
I guess I have no choice.
What choice?
There is no choice.
The summary report isn't finished yet.
We're working overtime tonight.
I still have to report to Deputy Corps Commander Liang tomorrow.
Give me the bag.
Yes, sir.
The commander asked you to wait in the room.
He'll come see you after the shift handover.
Okay, thank you.
You're welcome.
What a coincidence.
What coincidence?
Chief.
I've seen this sand table before.
The battlefield sand table from that campaign.
You've seen it?
Alright.
Coming to see me in such a hurry,
what's the matter?
Venting your grievances?
Filing a complaint?
Or do you have other requests?
Don't read from a script when talking to me.
I don't like it.
Chief.
If you put it that way,
I won't dare to speak.
Is that so?
You've always done things your own way.
Since when are you afraid to speak?
Go ahead.
Yes, sir.
I'm here to make a profound self-criticism.
Brigade Commander.
Do you think Guo Zijian
can get through this?
Hard to say.
It depends on whether he can realize
the mistakes he made in the exercise.
You played chess with the Chief for half the night,
and this is all the info you got?
We played for half the night,
but about the exercise,
he didn't mention a single word.
It doesn't look good for him.
I wouldn't go that far.
But I'm guessing,
during the establishment of the Wind Rider Battalion,
I figure,
Deputy Corps Commander Liang
hit plenty of walls with those experts.
The clash between new reforms and traditional thinking,
it's a miracle he didn't end up
badly battered.
Yeah.
So I assume,
regarding the Wind Rider Battalion,
during this exercise,
the problems that were exposed
have made the Chief
firmly make up his mind.
What do you mean?
In yesterday's chess game,
he had me wiped out.
Not a single piece was left.
Self-criticism?
That's a first.
In my impression,
you, Guo Zijian, are always on the side of truth.
Even if sometimes,
you bow to authority or circumstances,
or even emotions,
deep down inside,
you still feel incredibly noble.
Am I right?
Chief, I'm serious this time.
I'm serious, too.
I believe
the failure of this exercise
is primarily my own fault.
Is that so?
Did I hear you right?
Commander,
my usual way of thinking,
just as you mentioned earlier,
always involves some self-righteousness
that affects my judgment.
Therefore,
when faced with conflicts or difficulties,
including certain objective events,
I tend to blame external factors.
Stop beating around the bush.
Get straight to the point.
Yes, sir.
This time,
in terms of personnel deployment alone,
I made many mistakes.
Without fully understanding Wang Qilin,
I took the heavy burden of deciding the Wind Rider Battalion's fate
and handed it to him too easily.
This was my biggest mistake.
Also,
the deployment of Yang Maolin.
Another King of Soldiers.
Tell me about it.
Obviously, Long Yuanshan
understands him better than I do.
Yet I still delivered him right into Long Yuanshan's hands.
This was caused by my overconfidence
and severe underestimation of the enemy.
Continue.
Second,
our internal dynamics.
Due to my personality traits,
the internal operations of our command system
stalled,
and even some problems that shouldn't have occurred
were not addressed in time.
Third,
in terms of force composition,
I failed to balance everything.
Due to my overthinking and hesitation,
the air assault forces assigned to us
were not utilized at all.
Coupled with the improper use of the special ops platoon,
and inadequate integration of other new-type forces,
it resulted in
a complete failure to demonstrate
the unique strengths of our new-type combat battalion.
Fourth,
in urban offensive and defensive operations,
the effort and research we invested
were still insufficient.
As a result, once on site,
we found it was a completely different story.
Therefore,
the officers and soldiers couldn't adapt,
and fought many disorganized battles.
Fifth,
the casualty recovery system
was inaccurate and unrefined.
This time,
if Zeng Muhan hadn't stepped up
in the final stage,
we would have never been able to complete
the siege on the town hall.
Therefore,
from my perspective as the battalion commander alone,
this battle was lost long ago.